STONE CRAWLER 

A prequel to Before the Great Beyond, this game 
builds on the previously established combat system
in the game with the Sword Techniques being used for
different weapons and the gameplay being less linear with
graphics as well.

Developed by: Kobe Runnels

-------------------------------------------------------------------

Table of Contents:
1. Stone Crawler 
2. Basic Controls
3. Dungeon Crawling
4. Combat
5. Spells
6. Fortunes
7. Tips and Tricks

-------------------------------------------------------------------

1. Stone Crawler

Stone Crawler is a dungeon crawling rpg that has you making your way
through the Scilo, a mysterious prison that you have found yourself in.
Your main objective is to make your way to the top layer of the dungeon
through navigating through the mazes, encountering spirits and humans
that live in the dungeon, and knowing how to manage your health and what
kind of battles you're willing to face. As you're making choices in the
game, your character's personality will alter and their personality will
determine what kinds of spirits or humans will want to join you, the
course you'll take through the game, and the ending.

2. Basic Controls

Stone Crawler mainly uses simple arrow navigation menus with the enter key
being used to accept a selection (sometimes certain menus will also provide
instructions). When you are in a dungeon the M key can be used to pull up 
the menu in order to look at your status, use fusion on party members, look
at weapons, and more. The enter key is used as an action button when
your player is over a specific tile (such as a chest or holes where you can enter shops).

3. Dungeon Crawling

The main focus of the game will be the progression of your character through
a dungeon that you are assigned to infiltrate. Inside each dungeon, your 
character is represented with the ☺ character, enemy guards are represented
with the Ω character, holes in the wall that have shops inside are represented
with the ╬ character, chests with cash inside are reprented with the Θ while
opened chests are represented with the φ. Finally the main boss of the dungeon
will have the same sprite as the character, when approaching any dungeon enemy
the player will be forced to decide whether they want to fight or talk with the
enemy. If the player talks with the enemy, they have the potential of avoiding
the fight if they're able to convince said enemy to let them pass (for bosses
you will have to spare them or get them on your side). All battles in the dungeons
besides the boss and guard battles are random encounters and can be found with the
top left box indicating how close the player is to a random encounter battle.

4. Combat

When entering combat, the player will be given the option to select which weapon
they will use in combat or default to the first weapon in their inventory. There
are a total of six weapon types: Swords, Axes, Lances, Guns, Bows, and Combination
Weapons that have their own specific moves and each enemy represents a type of 
weapon (which if recruited and used in fusion to turn into a weapon they will
turn into said weapon). In combat, the enemy or the player and their party will go
first depending on their agility points. For the melee attacks such as slash and
thrust, a directional arrow key input is used to determine what direction you hit
the enemy (later on some may even show which direction is their weakness). If the player
has a high enough defense stat, they may be able to block out all the damage from the enemy
but at the cost of the enemy getting stronger so be careful. During combat the player
is also able to use fusion on their (non human) party members in order to either make
themselves stronger or gain another weapon if they are desparate in a fight (the fusion option
can be accessed in the Party Member Commands option). Non human allies are given commands
once the player has done their action and the non human members are given the option of
either attacking with a normal attack based on their weapon type or they can convince the
enemy to either join the party or listen to the party member leader which is determine by their
personality and the enemy's personality. Another way that enemy spirits can be recruited is
through capturing them by using a net, the success of the capture is random but if the enemy
has more health than you the capture will fail so be careful.

5. Spells

The player is able to channel the power of the high spirit energy in the dungeon
in order to perform spells. Here are the basic spells that the player can use
throughout the game (they are available in the "Extra Commands" option):

Fusion - You are able to fuse together spirits in order to turn them into weapons or fuse
	 them with yourself (at shops you will find a machine that can fuse two spirits together)

Attack Spells:
Plasma - Fire a bolt of plasma at an enemy
Magic Sword - Create magic blades that can slash at the enemy

Defensive Spells:
Aid - (Uses max health stat instead of health) Heal everyone at full health
Create Spirit - Create an ally based on your own stats

Each spell will have a chance at leveling up when the player levels up

6. Fortunes

At the start of each day, the player is given a fortune that can change what could happen
during the game, the following is a list of the fortunes and their benefits.

Sun - If your personality aligns more with the values of light then you will have +1 defense
Opening - Starting a new friendship with a human will lead to bonuses
Action - Regular attacks will do more damage
Climax - Your max health increases by 1 
Thought - Enemies will be willing to make deals
Reminisce - You will earn money based off of how many enemies you spared
Twilight - If your personality aligns more with the values of neutrality then you will have +1 defense
Journey - You will regain 5 health each time you go up a floor
Freedom - If you fuse with a spirit you will not become a half demon
Pause - Enemy encounter rate will decrease
Realization - You will earn more experience in combat
Ending - If you die in combat you will be revived once
Moon - If your personality aligns more with the values of darkness then you will have +1

7. Tips and Tricks

If you have certain human characters recruited they could potentially help you
recruit even more depending on their relationship (such as being friends,relatives, or
sharing similar beliefs).

The shops not only buys weapons from you but also sells weapons that change
depending on your stats in the game

Stocking up on ammunition is important as the gun and bow weapons can act as a helpful
burst of damage (at the risk of missing which can be found with the percentage gauge)

It's important to know when a fight is not going the way you intended, if you find yourself
in such a situation and you cannot talk your way out of it and you have a spare spirit ally,
transforming them into a weapon could prove useful as their stats will transfer into the weapon.

It's not required but having food with you (which you can buy from shops) can allow you to 
heal when saving the game and may even increase your max health.
